<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ulysse Pasquier</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ulysse Pasquier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ulysse Pasquier {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[R] Plotting results from extRemes package - Extreme Value Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/r-plotting-results-from-extremes-package-extreme-value-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-plotting-results-from-extremes-package-extreme-value-analysis/</guid>
      <description>If you are familiar with Extreme Value Analysis (EVA) in R you will have likely come across the extRemes package, written by Eric Gilleland. While I am not (yet!) an expert in EVA, I have found this package to be quite accessible.
The package’s main function, ‘fevd()’, fits an extreme value distribution to data. Methods for plotting are available for objects of class ‘fevd’ to produce diagnostics and result plots, such as a return level plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COP21: The Anchor to the Storm in Paris</title>
      <link>/post/cop21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cop21/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally written for the EnvEast Doctoral Training Partnership student blog. EnvEast is a collaboration between three UK universities, including University of East Anglia where I am carrying out my PhD. The blog can be found here
&amp;ldquo;Fluctuat Nec Mergitur&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Battu par les flots, mais ne sombre pas. Tossed by the sea, but not sunk.&amp;rdquo;
The centuries-old motto, which appears on the French capital&amp;rsquo;s crest, has been a central rallying cry in the wake of the Paris attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The environmental paradox behind the Tianjin explosions</title>
      <link>/post/tianjin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tianjin/</guid>
      <description>From water scarcity to air pollution, without forgetting world-leading greenhouse gas emissions, China is facing a multi-faceted environmental crisis. I was able to witness the extent of the issue first hand when I studied Environmental Management at Tsinghua University in Beijing as part of a joint program with the French university Mines ParisTech. The resounding blow of the August 12th explosions in Tianjin - which killed over a hundred people - has now pulled me back to that time spent in the &amp;ldquo;Middle Kingdom&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>