<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on Ulysse Pasquier</title>
    <link>/tags/france/</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on Ulysse Pasquier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ulysse Pasquier {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lies About France&#39;s Alleged War on Islam</title>
      <link>/blogpost/the-lies-about-france-alleged-war-on-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/the-lies-about-france-alleged-war-on-islam/</guid>
      <description>Another article of mine published in Areo Magazine. I wrote this in the aftermath of Samuel Paty&amp;rsquo;s assassination, the French teacher who was beheaded by a terrorist for having shown the Charlie Hebdo caricatures to his students during a class on free speech. The international reaction to Emmanuel Macron&amp;rsquo;s eulogy for Paty was perplexing. It showed a deep misunderstanding of the French context and sometimes even attempts to sow division by spreading false information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COP21: The Anchor to the Storm in Paris</title>
      <link>/post/cop21-the-anchor-to-the-storm-in-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cop21-the-anchor-to-the-storm-in-paris/</guid>
      <description>This post was originally written for the EnvEast Doctoral Training Partnership student blog. EnvEast is a collaboration between three UK universities, including University of East Anglia where I am carrying out my PhD. The blog can be found here
&amp;ldquo;Fluctuat Nec Mergitur&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Battu par les flots, mais ne sombre pas. Tossed by the sea, but not sunk.&amp;rdquo;
The centuries-old motto, which appears on the French capital&amp;rsquo;s crest, has been a central rallying cry in the wake of the Paris attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>