<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religion on Ulysse Pasquier</title>
    <link>/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religion on Ulysse Pasquier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ulysse Pasquier {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lies About France&#39;s Alleged War on Islam</title>
      <link>/blogpost/the-lies-about-france-alleged-war-on-islam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/the-lies-about-france-alleged-war-on-islam/</guid>
      <description>Another article of mine published in Areo Magazine. I wrote this in the aftermath of Samuel Paty&amp;rsquo;s assassination, the French teacher who was beheaded by a terrorist for having shown the Charlie Hebdo caricatures to his students during a class on free speech. The international reaction to Emmanuel Macron&amp;rsquo;s eulogy for Paty was perplexing. It showed a deep misunderstanding of the French context and sometimes even attempts to sow division by spreading false information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid the Tribal Trap of Stories</title>
      <link>/blogpost/how-to-avoid-the-tribal-trap-of-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/how-to-avoid-the-tribal-trap-of-stories/</guid>
      <description>A new piece of mine was featured in Areo Magazine. Here is a synopsis:
In Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind, Yuval Noah Harari highlights the importance of stories (religious, national, etc&amp;hellip;) as the basis for human cooperation and of our modern societies. Stories are able to fill that role because of the way they shape how we think and provide shared morals. Cognitive research shows that we use analogy-based mental models to interpret and understand our reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>