<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>admin on Ulysse Pasquier</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in admin on Ulysse Pasquier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ulysse Pasquier {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>“We can’t do it on our own!”—Integrating stakeholder and scientific knowledge of future flood risk to inform climate change adaptation planning in a coastal region</title>
      <link>/publication/env-sci-pol1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/env-sci-pol1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daenerys&#39; Descent into Madness</title>
      <link>/blogpost/daenerys-descent-into-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/daenerys-descent-into-madness/</guid>
      <description>Madness in literature and film is a powerful and gripping theme at the center of many classic tragic stories. The psychology of anti-heroes moving towards their seemingly inevitable downfall raises deep questions over our minds&amp;rsquo; capacity for self-destruction. Daenerys Targaryen from Game of Thrones very much follows this character arc in her transformation from a just and lovable Khaleesi into the Mad Queen. The burning of King&amp;rsquo;s Landing in Season 8 Episode 5 had all the ingredients to fulfil a descent into madness worthy of Shakespearian plays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid the Tribal Trap of Stories</title>
      <link>/blogpost/areo1/how-to-avoid-the-tribal-trap-of-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/areo1/how-to-avoid-the-tribal-trap-of-stories/</guid>
      <description>A new piece of mine was featured in Areo Magazine. Here is a synopsis:
In Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind, Yuval Noah Harari highlights the importance of stories (religious, national, etc&amp;hellip;) as the basis for human cooperation and of our modern societies. Stories are able to fill that role because of the way they shape how we think and provide shared morals. Cognitive research shows that we use analogy-based mental models to interpret and understand our reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An integrated 1D–2D hydraulic modelling approach to assess the sensitivity of a coastal region to compound flooding hazard under climate change</title>
      <link>/publication/nat-haz1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nat-haz1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Deneuve, #MeToo, and the Fracturing Within Feminism</title>
      <link>/blogpost/deneuve/catherine-deneuve-me-too-and-the-fracturing-within-feminism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/deneuve/catherine-deneuve-me-too-and-the-fracturing-within-feminism/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to write an opinion piece for Quillette, an online magazine on Science, Tech and Politics.
When 100 women, including Catherine Deneuve, signed a letter warning over potential excesses of the MeToo movement, they faced a serious backlash. I argue that their nuanced view is valuable and is not only compatible with the fundamental message behind #MeToo, but can also help it lead to concrete change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delving into Dreams</title>
      <link>/blogpost/dreams/delving-into-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/dreams/delving-into-dreams/</guid>
      <description>The portrayal of dreams in movies and books is a challenging task which often leads to fascinating results. Here I look at the links between Inception and Shutter Island and how a short poem by Edgar Allan Poe could very well have inspired both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychos &amp; Lambs</title>
      <link>/blogpost/psycho/psychos-and-lambs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogpost/psycho/psychos-and-lambs/</guid>
      <description>Looking aimlessly for something to do on a Sunday afternoon, I finally found myself watching Psycho by Alfred Hitchcock. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I had seen the classic horror-thriller but for some reason the film grabbed my attention and did not let go for the rest of that day. As Norman Bates presented his collection of stuffed birds to his would-be victim, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel I had already come across this somewhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/author/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/author/admin/</guid>
      <description>I am a Postdoctoral Researcher in the Earth and Environmental Sciences Area at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory based in Berkeley, California. My research focuses on the physical processes that drive the urban environment and hydro-climate. I am particularly interested in helping cities better understand and prepare for the impacts of climate change on flood risk and water scarcity.
My PhD thesis at the University of East Anglia and the Tyndall Centre for Climate Change Research looked at future flood risk and the adaptation process to the impacts of climate change in coastal areas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>